Andy Gonçalves

Engineering Manager

∅ (+351) 93 502 44 10
⋈ andygoncalves.pt@gmail.com
ndygoncalves.com
andygoncalves
seekandystroy



General

Traits Enthusiastic, straightforward, team player. Love to learn and hear different points of view. A true believer in honest feedback, growing people, and data-backed decisions.

Interests Leadership and management. Agile. Distributed systems and cloud computing.

Experience Engineering management. Architecture and implementation of the back-end of cloud applications. Team leading. Implementation of all the stack levels of web applications. Some web development. Master thesis in cloud computing.

Life Biker, gamer, kickboxer.

Professional Experience

2022-now Fidel API, (7 months), Engineering Manager, Stream.

Managing the team responsible for the new Stream product.

People management and delivery. Remote management.

2020–2022 Talkdesk, (1 year, 6 months), Engineering Manager, CCaaS.

2020 Talkdesk, (5 months), Associate Engineering Manager, CCaaS.

Managing two of the core teams of the product.

People management and delivery. Remote management.

2016–2020 Talkdesk, (4 years), Software Engineer, CCaaS.

Developing, scrum mastering, and team leading.

Designing and developing the new core systems of the product, responsible for routing calls. Maintaining the legacy call routing systems.

2013–2016 Safira/KPMG, (2 years, 5 months), Software Developer, IT for financial services.

Full-stack development of web applications, mobile web applications, and middlewares, for banks and insurance companies, using IBM technologies.

Education

2011–2013 Masters in Computer Science Engineering, Nova University, Lisbon, 17/20. 2 years MSc (Eng), focus on distributed systems. Thesis in cloud computing, grade of 18/20.

2008–2011 **Diploma in Computer Science Engineering**, Nova University, Lisbon, 15/20. 3 years BSc (Eng).

Technical Skills

General $\,$ OO/functional programming, TDD, SOA and Microservices, event-driven architectures, SQL, NoSQL.

Languages Ruby, Elixir (main ones). Java, Javascript, HTML5.

Last updated: 2022-08-10